Finding Aid for the Rob Roy Purdy Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Rob Roy Purdy Papers
2010-2011
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0348
9.24 linear feet
Scope and Content Note:
These papers are contained in 22 Hollinger boxes comprising 9.174 linear feet of manuscript material and are made up of these series:
Writings
Academic Career
1956 Fugitive Reunion
Administrative Career
Writings by Others
Publications
Biographical Note
Rob Roy Purdy was born in Pensacola, Florida in 1914. He died in Nashville on March 24, 1988 at the age of 74. He graduated from Davidson College, and came to Vanderbilt in 1937. After receiving his master degree he taught at Florence State College in Alabama for a year and served for two years in the Navy during World War II. He then returned to Vanderbilt for his Ph.D. in English. He became a member of the Vanderbilt English Faculty, and rose to the rank of full professor teaching courses in Anglo-Saxon Literature and Chaucer and in Shakespeare and Southern American Literature. In 1959 Professor Purdy became Vice Chancellor of Academic Affairs at the University. At his retirement in 1979 he was awarded the titles of Professor of English, Emeritus and Senior Vice-Chancellor Emeritus.
He was a member of the Committee of Educational Inquiry at Vanderbilt, one of ten such committees sponsored by the Carnegie Foundation in U.S. and Canadian Universities, and in 1956-57 he was the General Chairman of all ten committees. Dr. Purdy was director of the Vanderbilt University Press from 1957 to 1959 and Chairman of the University Committee on Athletics.
He edited for publication the many hours of tape from the 1956 Fugitive Reunion. The finished work was published in May 1958 with the title Fugitives’ Reunion: Conversations at Vanderbilt, May 3 -5, 1956.
He was married to Frances Edwards Purdy, and they had three sons.
- Writings by Purdy
  - “The Rise of the Bluestockings” - term paper (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Platonic Tradition in Early English Literature - thesis by Rob Roy Purdy under the direction of Walter Clyde Curry (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Platonic Tradition in Early English Literature (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Platonic Tradition in Early English Literature (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Platonic Tradition in Early English Literature (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - “Chaucer and Cleopatra” - paper - 3 typescript copies (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - “Chaucer Scholarship in England and America: A Review of Recent Trends” - typescript (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - “Chaucer Scholarship in England and America: A Review of Recent Trends” - pamphlet reprint (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - “The Friendship Motif in Middle English Literature” reprinted from Vanderbilt Studies in the Humanities,Vol. I, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Review of Agnus Castus. Middle English Herbal Reconstructed from various manuscripts. With correspondence (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Academic Career – Courses – Old English
  - Tests and quizzes (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Tests and quizzes (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Tests and quizzes (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Academic Career - Courses - Old English
  - Notes for Anglo-Saxon Poetry (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Anglo-Saxon Reports (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Academic Career - Courses - Chaucer
  - English 315 - Notes (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - English 315 - Notes (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - English 315 - Notes (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - English 315 - Notes (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - English 315 - “The Canterbury Pilgrims - Mural Paintings by Ezra Winter (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Notes, papers, and other materials (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - House of Fame (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - English 220 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Academic Career - Chaucer - Collection of Pamphlets and Reprints
  - Baugh, Albert Croll “Thomas Chaucer, One Man or Two?” (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Braddy, Haldeen “The Historical Background of the Parlement of Foules”
    Brown,Carleton “The Man of Law’s Head-link and the Prologue of the Canterbury Tales”
    Cunningham, J. V. “The Literary Form of the Prologue to the Canterbury Tales
    Dempster, Germaine “Manly’s Conception of the Early History of the Canterbury Tales”
  - Donaldson, E.Talbot “Chaucer’s Final –e” (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Dunn, Thomas F. “The Manuscript Source of Caxton’s Second Edition of the Canterbury Tales”
  - Goddard, H. C. “Chaucer’s Legend of Good Women” (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Hamilton, Marie P. “The Credentials of Chaucer’s Pardoner
  - Jones, Richard F. “ A Conjecture on the Wife of Bath’s Prologue” (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Kuhl, Ernest P. “Chaucer’s ‘My Maistre Bukton’”
    Linn, Irving “The Arming of Sir Thopas”
    Manly, John Matthews “Three Recent Chaucer Studies”
    Moore, Arthur K. “Chaucer and Matheolus”
  - Parr, Johnstone “The Date and Revision of Chaucer’s Knight’s Tale” (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Pratt, Robert “Was Chaucer’s Knight’s Tale Extensively Revised After the Middle of 1390?”; “Chaucer Borrowing from Himself”; “Geoffrey Chaucer, Esq. and Sir John Hawkwood”; “ A Note on Chaucer’s Lollius”; “The Importance of Manuscripts for the Study of Medieval Education, as Revealed by the Learning of Chaucer”; “A Note on Chaucer and the Policraticus of John of Salisbury”; “The Order of the Canterbury Tales”
  - Rickert, Edith “Was Chaucer a Student at the Inner Temple?” (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Severs, J. Burke “The Clerk’s Tale” (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Slaughter, Eugene E. “Clerk Jankyn’s Motive”; “Chaucer’s Pandarus:
    Virtuous Uncle and Friend”
    Smith, Roland M. “Two Chaucer Notes Three Notes on the Knight’s Tale”
    Tatlock, J.S.P. “The Canterbury Tales in 1400”
  - Starr, Herbert “Oaths in Chaucer’s Poems” (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Stearns, Marshall “A Note on Chaucer’s Attitude Toward Love”; A Note on Chaucer’s Use of Aristotelian Psychology”
  - Young, Karl “ Aspects of the Story of Troilus and Criseyde”; Chaucer’s ‘Troilus and Criseyde’ as Romance”; “Chaucer and Aulus Gellius” (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Other writings about Chaucer and other English literature subjects may be found in the series Writings by Others.
- Academic Career - Courses - Shakespeare
  - English 210 - History of Drama (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - English 320A (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - English 320A (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - English 320A (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - English 320B - Teaching notes (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - English 320B - Teaching notes (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - English 320 - Teaching notes (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - English 320 - Teaching notes (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - English 320 - Teaching notes (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - English 320 - Exams (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Academic Career – other courses
  - English 240 and S 442 - exam questions and notes (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Southern Literature - teaching notes (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - English 305 - 2 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Platonism (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Platonism (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Platonism (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Platonism (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Platonism (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Platonism (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Platonism (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Platonism (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Academic Career - Collected material by date
  - Final report of the Committee on the Senior College and the Committee on the Junior College, February 23, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Report of the Junior College Curriculum Committee, February 6, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Student Christian Association of V.U., 1951 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Statistical Tables of Peabody - Vanderbilt Affiliation, Summer 1947 - Fall 1950 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Men’s residences - papers (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Peabody College - Plan of Cooperation with Vanderbilt University, February 1952 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Curriculum Committee Reports, May 6, 1952, April 7, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Report - “ Some Curricular Developments in U.S. Colleges, February 1953 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Committee on the Un-American Activities, February 25 - 27, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - WVU “The Voice of Vanderbilt”, (1954) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Memorandum - “Organization of the Schools and Colleges of Vanderbilt University” (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Report of the Curriculum Committee, May 10, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Teacher Training - Aspen Conference, 1958 - 59 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - “Comments by Randall Jarrell, May 13, 1957; “What the Colleges are Doing” Fall 1959 and other articles (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Dr. Richmond C. Beatty Project, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Academic Career - Collected material by date
  - Isabel Howell, 1933, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings - Walter Clyde Curry and others, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Newspapers clippings - Caroline Gordon and Allen Tate, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Vanderbilt Literary Symposium, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Vanderbilt Literary Symposium, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Vanderbilt Literary Symposium, Brainard Cheney, Sam Davis facsimile letter and other, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Vanderbilt Literary Symposium and other programs, newspaper clippings, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Vanderbilt Literary Symposium, newspaper clippings and obituary for Richard Weaver, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper clippings – Vanderbilt faculty and Alexander Heard, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Vanderbilt Literary Symposium, newspaper clippings, and correspondence cards, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Randall Stewart Memorial Collection, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Donald Davidson – correspondence, programs, newspaper clippings, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Vanderbilt Literary Symposium; newspaper clippings, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Academic Career - Collected material by date
  - Correspondence and newspaper clippings on English faculty, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings and reviews, note from Walter C. Curry, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Vanderbilt Literary Symposium programs, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Book review “Real Tragedy of the South, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper articles and reviews, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Vanderbilt Literary Symposium program; VU Public Lecture Series program, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Vanderbilt Literary Symposium program, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - “50 Candles for the Fugitives” Special edition newspaper, 1972; April 19, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 1976-77 - Allen Tate - correspondence and newspaper clippings (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - James Dickey - newspaper articles, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Academic Career – Statements and Papers
  - Proposed Freshman Course “Culture of the West” (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Statements on the Humanities by VU and other faculty (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Statements on the Humanities by VU and other faculty (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Statements on the Humanities by VU and other faculty (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Statements on the Humanities by VU and other faculty (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Papers on Liberal Education (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Papers on Liberal Education (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Papers on Liberal Education (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Academic Career
- 1956 Fugitive Reunion - Transcripts
  - Reel 1, May 3, 1956, 3:00PM Neely Auditorium (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Reel 2, May 3, 1956, 3:00 PM Neely Auditorium (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Reel 3, May 3, 1956, 6:00 PM Rand Hall (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Reel 4, May 3, 1956, 6:00PM Rand Hall (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Reel 5, May 3, 1956, Rand Hall Dinner, closed session number one (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Reel 6, May 3, 1956, 9:30 - 11:45 PM, Part II, closed Session number one (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Reel 7, May 3, 1956, 9:30 - 11:45 PM, Part III, closed session number one (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Reel 8, May 3, 1956, 9:30 - 11:45 PM, Part IV, closed session number one (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Reel 9, May 3, 1956, 9:30 - 11:45 PM, End of closed session number one (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Reel 10, May 4, 1956, 10:30am - Jesse Wills’ house, closed session number two (Box 7, Folder 10)
- 1956 Fugitive Reunion – Transcripts
  - Reel 11, May 4th, 10:30 - 4:00, Part III, closed session number two (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Reel 12, May 4th, 10:30 - 4:00, Part IV, closed session number two (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Reel 13, May 4th, 10:30 - 4:00, Part V, closed session number two (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Reel 14, May 4th, 10:30 - 4:00, Part VI, closed session number two (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Reel 15, May 4th, 10:30 - 4:00, Part VII, conclusion closed session number two (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Reel 16, May 5th, 10:00 - 12:00, Faculty lounge, Alumni Hall, Vanderbilt University, Part II, closed session number three (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Reel 17, May 5th, 10:00 -12:00 Faculty lounge, Alumni Hall, Vanderbilt University, Part III, closed session number three (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Reel 18, May 5th, 10:00 -12:00, Faculty lounge, Alumni Hall, Vanderbilt University, Part IV, conclusion closed session number three (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Reel 19, May 5th, 1:15 PM, Rand Hall Dining Room, Part II, closing session with summary comments by Robert Penn Warren (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Reel 20,May 4th, 6 - 8PM, Belle Meade Country Club (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Reel 21, May 4th, 8:30PM Neely Auditorium (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Academic Career
- 1956 Fugitive Reunion - Transcripts
  - Reel 22, May 4th, 8:30PM, Neely Auditorium (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Reel 23, May 4th, 8:30PM, Neely Auditorium (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Reel 24, May 4th, 8:30PM, Neely Auditorium (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Reel 25, May 4th, 8:30 P.M. Neely Auditorium (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Reel 26, May 4th, 8:30 P.M. Neely Auditorium (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Transcript corrections by William Y. Elliott (Box 9, Folder 6)
- 1956 Fugitive Reunion - Other
  - Correspondence, book reviews, and other (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, book reviews, and other (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence and other papers (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence and other papers (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence and other papers (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence and other papers (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Photograph of 5 Fugitives and Vanderbilt Alumnus, May - June 1956 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- 1967 Fugitive Collection
  - Correspondence and articles (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Other Fugitive materials
  - “The Fugitive Clippings and Comment” collected by Merrill Moore (Box 9, Folder 15)
    “The Fugitive Particular: John Crowe Ransom Critic” by Morgan Blum
- Academic Career – Carnegie Corporation – Committees of Educational Inquiry (CEI)
  - Quarterly reports, October, 1953; January, 1955; July, 1955; July 1956; October 1956; January 1957 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - CEI - Edgewater Conference, November 1952 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - CEI - Reading Review Notes, # 1 - 6, February - August 1953 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - CEI - Chicago Meeting, October 1953 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - CEI - Washington Meeting, October 1953 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - CEI - Organization and Purpose - A Pioneer Project Assessed (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - CEI - Stanford Report (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - CEI - Members (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - CEI - Newsletters, #1, #2, #3 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Academic Career – Liberal Arts Colleges
  - Proceedings of Oklahoma Conference (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Report - Aims of Liberal Education (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Reports - “The Plight of the Private Liberal Arts College”; Liberal Arts Education at the Mid-Century (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Report - The Humanities at Oberlin, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Academic Career - other
  - “An Academic Costume Code and Ceremony Guide” (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Publications concerning scholarship (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Guide to Scholarly Periodicals, 1958 - 59 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Anglo - Saxon - newspaper articles (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Teacher Education and Certification - Guide to Study (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Omicron Delta Kappa Leadership Honor Society, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Publications of the Southern Humanities Conference, 1949 - 58 (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Administrative Career - Speeches, Papers, Addresses
  - “Higher Education and Democracy” paper presented to the Coffee House Club, February 20, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - “Higher Education and Democracy” paper presented to the Coffee House Club, February 20, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - “The Fugitive Poets” paper presented to the Coffee House Club - drafts, notes, sources (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - “The Problem of Admisssions at Vanderbilt” in Vanderbilt Alumnus, Vol. 51, no. 3, November - December, 1965; “ A Summary of Athletic Grants-in-Aid Awarded by S.E.C. Member Schools in Sports Other than Football and Basketball for 1962 -63 Academic Year (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - “Admissions and Athletics” 1965 - 66 - Speech to Alumni (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Remarks at the Holland Society Dinner honoring Governor William H. Vanderbilt in New York City, February 20 - 21, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Alumni Club Speeches - Houston, Montgomery, and Tupelo, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - “The Alumni Mystique”, July 1971 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - “The Alumni Mystique” - notes and emendations (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Address to the Civitan Club, August 3, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Report on Athletics to Alumni Board with notes, May 13, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Remarks on Athletics at Board Meeting, April 30, with notes - May 1, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Remarks at memorial service for Jesse E. Wills, March 7, 1977, with correspondence (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Remarks at memorial service for Jesse E. Wills, March 7, 1977, with correspondence (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Memorial resolutions for Dorothy Minnich, Frank Blood, William N. Pearson (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Memorial resolutions for Donald Davidson, Walter Clyde Curry, Julia Hereford, Randall Stewart (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Commencement addresses - Florence State College, Montevallo, Scarritt, David Lipscomb College (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Administrative Career - Speeches, Papers, Addresses
  - “In Loco Parentis” papers and rough draft (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - “In Loco Parentis” papers and rough draft (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - “In Loco Parentis” papers and rough draft (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - “In Loco Parentis” papers and rough draft (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Speeches, with biographical note (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Speeches (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Speeches (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Speeches (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Speeches (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Speeches (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Speech material (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Speech material (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Speech material (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Speech material (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Speech material (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Speech material (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Speech material (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Speech material - Vanderbilt University (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Speech material - Admissions at VU (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Administrative Career - Speeches, Papers, Addresses
  - Chancellor’s Speeches (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Chancellor’s Speeches (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Chancellor’s Speeches (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Chancellor’s Speeches (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Chancellor’s Speeches (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Chancellor’s Speeches (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Chancellor’s Speeches - Alexander Heard (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Chancellor’s Speeches - Alexander Heard (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Chancellor’s Speeches - Alexander Heard (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Chancellor’s Speeches - Alexander Heard (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Administrative Career - Collection of Speeches and Addresses by others
  - Alexander Heard; Wendell Holladay; Harold Howe, II; Huston Smith (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Frank G. Dickey; Raymond J. Seeger (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - M.M. Chambers; Alvin C. Eurich; W. Allen Wallis (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Harvie Branscomb; Nathan Marsh Pusey (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Dean L. Beach in honor of Chancellor Branscomb; John S. Dickey; Louis E. Wolfson; N. Floyd McGowin (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Gerald Barradas with opinion and notes of Judge Robert N. Wilkin; Robert L. Hershey; Leo J. Raskind (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Spiro T. Agnew, Vice-President of U.S.; Richard M. Nixon, President U.S. (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Dr. Grayson Kirk, partial text of address, January 7, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 18)
- Administrative Career
  - Cruise, July 6 - 21, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trust papers - Minutes and other papers re: meeting, November 11 -12, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Board of Trust papers - Minutes and other papers re: meeting, November 11 -12, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Board of Trust papers - Executive Committee - Minutes - meetings, February 8, 1967 and June 27, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Board of Trust papers - agenda, November 10 - 11, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Board of Trust papers - Executive Committee, March 12, 1968 - November 30, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Board of Trust papers re: meeting, May 2 - 3, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Papers from the President to Presidents Conference, October 1 - 3, 1971; Washington, D.C. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Visit to Strategic Air Command Headquarters, October 20 - 21, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Vanderbilt University Alumni Association, London Tour, October 1 - 9, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Vanderbilt University Admissions - Key to Charts (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Vanderbilt University, Department of Athletics - Five Year Capital Improvements, June 7, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Athletics - articles and newspaper clippings (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Athletics - articles and newspaper clippings (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Campaign totals by Purpose/ Appendix II, III with correspondence (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Administrative Career
  - Campaign totals - copy for Dale Klaus (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Interrelated Programs in Liberal Arts (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Vanderbilt Policy (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Vanderbilt Policy (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Vanderbilt Student Communications with By-Laws Revisions (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Vanderbilt Student Communications with By-Laws Revisions (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Student Affairs - newspaper clippings (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Student Affairs - newspaper clippings (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Student and University Affairs - newspaper clippings (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Student and University Affairs - newspaper clippings (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Student and University Affairs - newspaper clippings (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Student and University Affairs - newspaper clippings (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Student and University Affairs - newspaper clippings (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Student and University Affairs - newspaper clippings (Box 15, Folder 14)
- Administrative Career
  - Student and University Affairs - newspaper clippings (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Student and University Affairs - newspaper clippings (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Student and University Affairs - newspaper clippings (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Student and University Affairs - newspaper clippings (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Students (Xerox copy - 99 pages and footnotes) (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Student Affairs at other universities - newspaper clippings (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Student Affairs at other universities - newspaper clippings (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Student Affairs at other universities - University of Chicago, Chicago Maroon (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Student Affairs at other universities - Chicago Maroon and other Chicago papers (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Student Affairs at other universities - Chicago and others (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Insurance information (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Writings by Others
  - Allen, Don Cameron “The Classical Scholarship of Francis Meres” (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Bandy, W.T. “Bulletin Baudelairien”
    Baugh, Albert C. “A Fraternity of Drinkers”
    Baughn, Denver Ewing “Sir Philip Sidney and the Matchmakers”
  - Beatty, Richmond C. “Whitman’s Political Thought”; “Allen Tate as Man of Letters” (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Bethurum, Dorothy “The Form of Aelfric’s Lives of the Saints; “Six Anonymous Old English Codes”; Review of Visions from Piers Plowman (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Blair, Lawrence “English Church Ales: with a Note on Church Fairs”; “ A List of Churchwardens’ Accounts” (Box 17, Folder 4)